# Marat Saytakov · iOS Software Engineer · Resume · CV

#### Introduction

My name is Marat Saytakov. I am an iOS software engineer with over 4 years of experience. I am proficient in Objective-C, but I prefer Swift.

I graduated from Moscow State Technical University, where I studied computer science and microchip programming. I have an <u>Engineer's degree</u> in Information Systems.

Currently I live in Moscow, but I am ready to relocate for the right position.

Skills Contact

Deep knowledge in Objective-C and Swift. Email Memory management, asynchronous behavior. Web: 99% crash-free apps. GitHu

Short-list: iOS SDK, Cocoa Touch, ARC, GCD, plain C, Xcode, design patterns, CocoaPods/Swift Package Manager, Crashlytics, Git, OOP, Protocol-Oriented Programming, Apple HIG.

Email: <a href="mailto:remarr@gmail.com">remarr@gmail.com</a>
Web: <a href="mailto:m4rr.ru">m4rr.ru</a>

GitHub: m4rr

LinkedIn: maratsaytakov

# Languages

Russian (native), English (fluent)

#### Collaboration

Apple **Swift contributor** on GitHub · 2016 I started contributing to Swift with small things. github.com/apple/swift

Code Mentor · 2015—Present

I am a code mentor, covering expertise of Swift, plain C, Objective-C and Xcode. <a href="mailto:codementor.io/m4rr">codementor.io/m4rr</a>

Moscow Coding School · 2015—Present

Mentoring students at an in-person Swift programming course. moscoding.ru/ios

CocoaHeads Moscow · 2013—Present

Active member of Moscow iOS/OS X developers community.

Given talks: <u>Size Classes (2014, in Russian)</u>

### **Employment**

Freelancing iOS developer · 2015—Present

Tested Upwork member. Top 30% in iOS Programming Test; Top 20% in Swift Test.

**WirelessHeads** · <u>pasteapp.me</u> · Oct. 2015—Present · Lead iOS Developer Working on Paste for iOS — clipboard history manager for Mac. Made decision on multiplatform sync of CoreData.

**Luuk** · <u>luuk.com</u> · October 2014—Sep. 2015 · Lead iOS Developer Luuk is the top beauty-industry startup in Moscow. I released both of the current versions of the apps, which were created in Swift. It has had 30k downloads in the first month and has been 99% crash free.

**RocketBank** · <u>rocketbank.ru</u> · Sep. 2013—Sep. 2014 · iOS Developer Released a RocketBank based MVP of a card-to-card mobile application, as well as developed the second version of RocketBank app with a fellow programmer.

**Aic** · <u>aic.ru</u> · August 2012—August 2013 · iOS Developer Prototyped a mobile app for <u>Money Inc</u>, a future banking concept. It is a simple way to manage your banking accounts.

# **Side Projects**

Moscow Underground Wi-Fi Auth  $\cdot$  m4rr.ru/mauth  $\cdot$  App Store  $\cdot$  GitHub Everyone in Moscow Metro has to waste a lot of time to get authorized thru overcomplicated Wi-Fi Captive portal. I solved this problem: this app takes care of authorization process for the user. Very popular among Muscovites. Open-source.

Chars · chars.cc · App Store

Beautiful and native way to type everything with Unicode characters on iOS.

Easy Percent · App Store

An easier and prettier calculator for taxes and reverse percentages.

Sochi Safety Guide · Ocloudesign · App Store

A personal safety guide for Russia.

#### Education

**Engineer's degree** in Information Systems at the Faculty of Cybernetics in Moscow State University of Radio-engineering, Electronics and Automation (<u>H+ for MIREA</u>) September 2007—July 2012